

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Over 4 years commercial experience in Software Development and over 3 years in 3D Game Development. Proficient in multiple design, administrative and project management software/application with high adaptability to new software/application. Excellent knowledge in software development methodologies and best practices. Always eager to learn and enthusiastic about putting own skill sets to good use on various platforms. Fluent in Malay, Cantonese and effective in the English language.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

THG (2017-PRESENT)

Role : Engineering Manager API Gateway (April 2021 – Present)

Responsibilities

- Led and architect Software as a Service (SaaS) projects in several aspects; Gateway, Authentication, Service Account Management, User Management, Data and Configuration segregation
- Built a gateway solution to expose internal platforms to external clients.
- Built an audited internal tool with React to successfully manage gateway configurations.
- Manage a team of 2 Software Engineers with Lead Engineers and additional Senior Software Engineers on the pipeline.
- Proposed architectural roadmaps to improve scalability and performance.
- Implemented processes to automate on boarding new clients onto the gateway.

Role : Engineering Manager Courier and Delivery Service (July 2018 – March 2021)

Responsibilities

- Manage a team of 8-9 Java Software Engineers with various skill sets and skills levels ranging from Junior Java Software Engineer to Senior Java Software Engineer.
- Responsible for team's well-being, improvements as well as technical stack improvements.
- Raise automation improvements to simplify repetitive processes reducing the need for manual intervention from the team and improving overall focus and productivity by 20-30%
- Manage project requirements, scope, risk and timeline effectively, delivering based on priority and value.
- Retrofit ever changing business requirements into team's day to day stream of work.
- Reduced major incidents from once every 1-2 week to once in 2 quarters by proposing metrics and monitoring improvements.
- Implemented configuration simplification which contributed to cost saving of more than £1M a year.

Role : Software Engineer (June 2017 – July 2018)

Responsibilities

- Led a technical project team and successfully delivered additional features in internal customer service tools to support GDPR related requests, evading potential non-compliance fines of €20 million or 4% of annual global turnover whichever is greater.
- Responsible for the design, development and improvements of an automated shipping allocation and pricing service written on the Java platform.
- Develop and maintain tools and scripts to automate workflow.



- Create scripts to migrate and/or replicate over 500,000 rows of data across several database tables.
- Manage and improve team's configuration tool built on AngularJS.
- Create and maintain a visual representation of data for business and logistics.
- Maintain, refactor and redesign legacy applications.
- Establish code style to increase maintainability and readability.
- Communicate with internal and external stakeholders to gather and deliver requirements while closely following supplied system specification documentation.
- Primarily working with the following technologies; Java, Spring Boot, Tomcat, MS SQL Server, AngularJS, ActiveMQ, Camel, Grafana, Kibana

BIG ANT STUDIOS (2011-2013)

Big Ant Studios, one of the largest game developers in Australia, develop premium games content for platforms that include the Sony PlayStation2, PlayStation3, PlayStation4, Nintendo Wii, Microsoft Xbox360, and PC. Develop games using SCRUM methodology.

Project: Masquerade: Baubles of Doom, Original IP (Xbox One, Xbox360, PS4, PS3, PC)

Roles:

- Assistant Associate Producer/Scrum Master (January 2013 September 2013)
- Technical Artist (January 2012 September 2013)
- 3D Animator (December 2011 September 2013)
- 3D Environment Artist (April 2011 April 2013)
- 3D Artist (February 2011 January 2013)

ACE EDVENTURE (FREELANCE) (2013)

Project : ChemQuest Educational Game (iOS, Android)

Role : Technical Visual Effects Artist (Freelance)

RELEVANT TECHNICAL SKILLS

DEVELOPMENT

Java	Spring Boot	AngularJS	React	
Jenkins	C#	HTML	JS	
CSS	SQL	XML	PHP	
C++	С	Gradle	iOS/Swift	
Android	Git	Docker	Mel Scripting	
Lua	MQL4/5	Groovy		

3D GAME & DESIGN

Adobe Creative Suite	Autodesk Mava	Unitv	V-Rav
Cinema4D	Autodesk MeshMixer	123D Make	Real Flow
ZBrush	FXHome	Particle Illusion	Unreal

Faceshift



OTHER EXPERIENCES

Company/Organisation Role

Triplaxis 3D Printing Studio Business & Technology Development

Taylor's University Lakeside Campus Research Assistant

Star Group (Taylor's University)

Design Support, Team Lead

Amore Productions Cinematographer

Freelance photography Photographer/Visual Story-Teller

EDUCATION

Course : Bachelor of Software Engineering (HONS) Dual-Award (2014 – 2017)

Award : 1st Class

Institution : University of the West of England & Taylor's University Lakeside Campus

Course : Diploma in Digital Animation (2007 – 2010)
Institution : The One Academy of Communication Design

CERTIFICATION

University of the West of England | Software Engineering Final Year: Full Scholarship 2016/17

• Faculty wide scholarship, awarded to only 2 students per academic year.

Taylor's University Lakeside Campus | School of Computing and IT: Dean's List Award 2014-2016

Prestigious award, awarded to students with CPA above 3.5